-(woman) Rolling, right?
-(man) Yes.
(woman) Doctor...
Doctor?
-Shall we?
-Yeah.
Ready.
(woman) Sir, how did Zaathi start?
Yes...
It was in Delhi.
We were a group of eight.
We were partying after this...
boring medical conference.
In the middle of it,
Dr. Gulati got a call.
One of his patients...
he was dying due to sepsis.
He didn't have enough money
to buy the emergency medicine
prescribed to him.
(sighs)
Lakhs.
It cost him lakhs
just for one injection only.
The same molecule is available
with another brand as well.
And that costs only ₹17,000.
Just some
generic medicine.
But that one
was not available anywhere.
Mysteriously out of stock.
Everywhere.
That night, that same night
that patient...
he passed away.
(mysterious score)
That night, on that table,
Zaathi was born.
As a supply chain for generic drugs.
A very humble beginning.
But we never imagined
it would lead to such a huge battle.
We never...
Mmm-mmm.
(engine rumbling)
-(gunshots)
-(shell casings clink)
(opening theme music)
(bell tolls)
(conch blowing)
-(train chugs)
-(faint station announcements)
(mysterious score)
Hello, sir?
I came out through the front exit.
Near the bike parking.
(man) Yeah, there. Walk straight.
Okay, sir.
Hello, sir. I'm K.P. Vinod.
Have you had lunch?
Lunch... No, sir.
Do you eat biryani?
Yeah. Sure, sir.
All right, come on.
It's a one-crore market.
Isn't it, sir?
I'm basically from Wayanad, sir.
I did my Bachelor of Pharmacy
in Kozhikode.
I was the Mysore University topper
for the Master of Pharmacy.
For a while,
I worked at a medical shop, too.
I joined RXLH after that.
So?
I am very much excited, sir.
Such a huge market
and working in a team
under a senior manager like you.
(chuckles)
What's the speciality here, sir?
This is the only place in Thrissur
that serves
boiled eggs with biryani.
That's the speciality.
Okay? Eat now.
(whimsical score plays)
My mom lives alone in our hometown.
She won't come here
even if I ask her to.
I worked at the same medical shop
as my mom.
So, I thoroughly know
about medicines.
I'm gonna rock this!
(quirky, whimsical music)
(engine idling)
(car door closes)
(car door shuts)
Stay here for the time being.
-A company bike is also here.
-Okay.
You can find a house later and move.
But on one condition.
-You must stay here alone.
-Okay.
Our company doesn't like
you "having company."
You had a long journey, right?
Go to your room, freshen up,
and get a good rest.
Okay. Thank you, sir.
And get ready in half an hour.
-What?
-(whimsical score)
What, you ask?
Shouldn't we start work?
-Why else would I come from Kochi?
-(mumbles) Okay, sir.
I gotta go back after inducting you.
Okay, sir. I'll be right back.
We've an urgent meeting at
the hospital. You've got 29 minutes.
Okay, sir.
(puzzling score)
Your keys.
All right.
(music turns jaunty)
Pseudomonas aeruginosa.
Streptococcus pneumoniae.
Staphylococcus aureus.
Sa...
Sa...?
Ugh!
I always forget this one!
Salmonella enterica.
Salmonella... enterica.
(jaunty score continues)
(in mild voice) Good morning, Doctor.
I am K.P. Vinod.
(in deep voice) Good morning, Doctor.
(in raised voice) Good morning, doctor.
I am K.P. Vinod.
Okay.
(latch clicks open)
(jaunty score)
(Alex) Hey.
This is the top hospital
on our list.
Marwellous.
Wow.
Such an auspicious hospital.
The best place to start my work.
(car lock beeps)
Are you gonna stand there?
(slow, uplifting score)
-(stretcher wheels squeaking)
-(indistinct chatter around)
(Alex) You'll have to
come here twice a week, at least.
Okay? Huh?
What are you doing, man?
It's my first day, sir.
-Not breaking a coconut for luck?
-Mom will do it at home.
That's great! Are you coming now?
(lively score)
-What's this, man?
-Coming, sir.
(light, upbeat music)
(music intensifies)
Keep your bag there.
(man) RXLH's new recruit is here.
Will I take any other bag
by mistake?
-(man) Are you new?
-Huh? Yes.
-I'm Davis.
-I'm Vinod. K.P. Vinod.
Vinod!
Go ahead.
-Leave the detailing book.
-No, sir. I've got it by heart!
(indistinct chatter)
The doctor won't see
anyone else today.
He just got a call.
His mother passed away.
He's leaving now.
(incoherent voices)
What an auspicious start!
What are you waiting for?
Get your bag.
Go on.
(whimsical music)
Ah, Alex. Come inside.
Come on!
-But she said he won't meet--
-Come!
(doctor) Get me their study papers.
The trip will be
only after two months, right?
Yes, sir.
We'll submit the visa documents
this week itself.
That's why I thought of signing them
now itself.
I won't be around this week.
Okay, sir.
Sir, he's our new recruit.
Vinod. K.P. Vinod.
(whimsical music continues)
The cremation is tomorrow.
You wanna give it a shot?
Palintos is taking care of it now.
How much are they doing it for?
Well, they said 350.
How much is the estimate, sir?
Above five.
Oh, no.
We'll need approval for that.
Forget it then.
This is your problem.
Approval, it seems!
Let me know
once the visa is approved.
Okay, sir.
What was that, sir?
Oh, that?
We have an offer.
If the doctor writes 200 prescriptions
with our medicine,
we offer him a trip to Switzerland.
We don't call it
an "offer," actually.
We call it an "efficacy study."
Well, he mentioned
Palintos and some 350...
What was that?
Oh, that one?
His mom kicked the bucket, right?
It was about
sponsoring her cremation.
That stupid Palintos team snatched it
for a mere 350 prescriptions.
And we've got
a hell lot of formalities.
(sighs)
Why don't you do this?
That doctor's father is alive.
Get his full details.
Then get approval.
If anything happens to him,
we should file our proposal first.
They snatched his mother.
But his father should be all ours!
The meeting must've started.
What meeting, sir?
There are some folks here
who despise us.
You know our cancer drug's offer...
I mean, study.
They're trying to stop it.
You must deal with all this
and learn.
Don't wait for me
to arrive from Kochi.
Rajiv Rao.
Isn't he on our list, sir?
-Nope.
-I see.
He must practise less, I guess?
There are quite a number of doctors
who practise a lot here.
You know this Rajiv Rao...
he's the best in the whole district.
Why isn't he on our list then?
What's our list, huh?
The ones who listen to us
are on our list.
Got it?
Rao must be here now.
He's a major troublemaker here.
Come!
And then there's Dr. Shakeer.
He was short of one prescription
to qualify for our Swiss trip.
It's beneficial only if our cancer drug
is prescribed in Stage 2.
(mysterious score)
You know what I did?
I asked the doctor to prescribe
the drug for Stage 4 patients.
The patient is gonna die anyway.
What difference does it make then?
-And then?
-Then what?
People tried to make it an issue.
Nonsense!
(man 1) Let Dr. Shakeer speak.
(man 2) Look at my prescription!
Sensite infusion thrice a week.
Coupled with other procedures,
it is a speciality drug.
When I, the oncologist, am here,
what is a mere physician doing here?
I really don't understand
the purpose of this meeting.
Simply wasting my time!
Relax. Relax.
Dr. Rajiv.
Dr. Shakeer...
The RXLH drug you prescribed,
this Sensite... it costs ₹2.5 lakh.
(Shakeer) Yeah, so?
I have the hospital price list.
Same drug, same molecule,
it is available at Zaathi
for just ₹7,000.
(Shakeer scoffs) Ridiculous!
This is a poor man. An auto driver.
Yet you're giving him this?
This Sensite?
And that, too, at this stage?
The molecule is what cures
the disease, not the brand.
(Shakeer scoffs) Bullshit!
Not the brand, it seems!
Doctor, that's a serious allegation.
Doctor, this is India.
There are thousands of companies
with poor manufacturing quality.
Brand is important.
-He's got a point.
-There's a study going on too, yeah?
Yes. Efficacy study.
Everything is
through the proper channel.
We've got the consent
from the patient as well.
That's the usual practice.
And this isn't some gift scheme
in the name of a study?
Doctor, now you're questioning
my integrity.
Hey, come on, Rajiv. Stop it.
Come back to the matter.
Does it not say in the study
that the patient has the right to
withdraw consent at any given time?
Yes.
So then?
Rajiv, move on from the study part.
-Sir, may I?
-Yes.
Brother, who is the patient to you?
My wife, sir.
When I buy something for myself,
I always look at the price.
Whether it is a shirt
or a mobile phone,
I go with the cheapest option
and also enquire with
at least ten sellers.
I have a daughter. Elina.
When she got unwell...
I didn't care about the money.
I took her to the best hospital
in the city.
We can buy a new phone or a shirt
whenever we want.
But is that the same
when it comes to people?
Sir...
I'm okay with the medicine
you prescribed.
I don't care about the money, sir.
Even if I have to sell
my autorickshaw...
or even...
sell my house,
I will buy this medicine for her.
I told this
at the pharmacy, sir.
I didn't create this issue.
Sir...
See?
I think the issue is resolved.
The bystander has no complaints.
Neither does the patient,
nor the doctor.
Then what's your problem, Dr. Rajiv?
(Shakeer scoffs)
I'm leaving, Doctor.
Patients are waiting.
His bloody Zaathi
and medicine sales!
I am also leaving.
Whether you choose Zaathi
or the hospital...
you'll have to face that question
pretty soon, Doctor.
So, better be ready with an answer.
Is there any doubt
what my answer will be?
Doctor...
No hard feelings.
It's just business.
(scoffs) Exactly.
(door squeaks opens)
-(door closes)
-Hmm!
Uh... you...
Doctor...
Come.
-How old is your daughter?
-What?
Your daughter, Elina.
What daughter?
I don't have a daughter.
All I have is a son.
I was just bluffing there.
Every week, you must visit
each ward and get a list.
Yes.
Of which doctors
are prescribing which medicines.
I gotta meet Alexander.
He's the purchase in-charge.
Okay.
We'll go to the nursing station
and the medical shop after that.
I'll do it myself, sir.
I've got quite a bit of
field training, after all!
Really? Do this then.
Visit the gynaec ward and the
medical shop outside the hospital.
Let's meet after that.
-Okay, sir.
-Fine. Go now.
Gynaec ward...
(playful score)
Good afternoon, sisters!
I am K.P. Vinod
from RX Life Healthcare Ltd.
How many patients were given
Cetfaclor this week?
You may ask the doctor.
Why ask them?
The gynaec doctors
are close allies of ours.
Really? Which doctor?
All of them.
They all prescribe
only our medicines. What to do!
Yet, I haven't seen you before.
-She is?
-She's the doctor.
Dr. Janaki.
Oh! Dr. Janaki!
(placid music)
You could've told me!
-It's no big deal!
-We're in the same field, after all!
She's quite friendly.
-Really?
-Yeah.
(cheerful score)
Please see if our medicines
are delivered on time.
Done.
Hello!
Doctor... Hi.
Hi, I am... Sorry.
I am new here. That's why.
It's fine. The gynae reps' slot
is on Wednesday.
See you then.
(placid music continues)
(mumbles) That was close.
Didn't ruin it.
(lively music)
(music continues)
(indistinct chatter)
(man) Okay, got it.
Thank you.
(energetic score)
(music fades)
Brother, good afternoon.
Can't you see the rush?
Come back later.
(mutters) Him and his lousy bag.
Good afternoon. I'm from RXLH.
So what? Can't you see the rush?
Is this the time for this?
Come back later.
(indistinct chatter)
(pharmacist) Yes,
I'll call after some time.
Brother...
How many units of Cetfaclor were sold
this week? It's for a survey.
-What is this now--
-The thing is
I'm here to survey this week's
oral antibiotic sales.
-I see! 750 BD, isn't it?
-Yeah.
Please wait here, brother.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
(woman 1) That's just 50 mg.
(woman 2) Are you a new recruit?
Yeah.
The previous guy from your company
kept all this stock here
under "personal intent."
-So?
-You take this away.
It's been lying here for a year now,
taking up space.
His damned survey!
If you don't take this away now,
it'll end up on the road.
(quirky score)
Hi, sir.
(Alex) What's this, huh?
You went for the survey
or to bring these boxes?
So embarrassing!
They gave this to me
when I went there for the survey.
The way you went there,
I expected this to happen.
-What's this, man?
-What can I do, sir?
All right, keep it here.
(man chuckles) The new rep
is lugging boxes!
(quirky score continues)
The sales had gone down
over the last two months
since we didn't have a rep.
To the right.
You have to bring them up now.
Of course, I will!
Just not like this.
It's for return.
Hello.
Keep it there.
-Where's it from?
-The shop near Marwellous Hospital.
Aswathy Medicals.
Medical reps should deliver stock,
not return it.
He's our new rep.
Vinod. K.P. Vinod.
We have a new product launch.
KydoXin.
You have to support us
regarding the stock, Swamy.
You make the prescriptions
reach the medical shops.
-We'll deal with the stock.
-Okay.
If you do enough business,
you'll find enough stock here.
That's what we want!
-All right. See you then.
-Okay.
Did you meet Dr. Sreenivasan?
No. We're going there now.
Catch hold of him.
He'll change the market.
All the best. Give it a shot.
(energetic beat plays)
This guy, Swamy, can change
our destiny if he wishes.
We shall change our destiny, sir.
You better.
I will. Which hospital is next?
Sure! Are we on a fun tour
of all the hospitals, little kid?
Go and figure it out yourself.
Once we meet Dr. Sreenivasan,
my duty will be over.
Start meeting the other doctors
on the list on your own.
-Okay, sir.
-And send me the reports correctly.
(woman) You guys go next, okay?
(indistinct background chatter)
Please don't ruin this.
He's the most annoying person
in this town.
Nah...
Wait and watch
how I impress him! Come.
Huh? Impress him?
-Just come, sir! (clear throat)
-What are you going to do?
Good evening, Doctor.
Hold on. Stay.
Then, check his vitals.
Yeah.
(bouncy score)
Good. Okay.
Okay.
Good evening, Doctor.
-Good evening.
-He is our new... rep.
Vinod.
K.P. Vinod.
Sir, for
your gram-negative infections,
why are you going for
secondary options?
You should not do that.
(mumbles) Stop it, Vinod.
Look at this latest issue of
Journal of Internal Medicine.
You should go for a safer,
fourth-generation medicine, sir.
If not,
you are making a mistake, sir.
(mumbles) Dude!
What?
What did you say now?
Sir, you should not prescribe
all these old medicines, sir.
What?
(mumbles) Stop it, Vinod.
Who are you to tell me
"you should not"?
No, Doctor...
(shouts) How dare you do that? Huh?
Vinod...
-Pharmacologically speaking, page 17--
-To hell with your journal! Come on!
I made a mistake, yeah?
(tense music)
Journal, sir...
Please...
(papers rustling)
Get lost! Idiot!
(man) What happened?
We were all waiting here,
but he cut the queue, right?
You deserve it!
Yeah, pick them up.
(people laughing)
(whimsical score)
(Vinod mutters) Shucks! Asshole.
(woman) He tried to act smart.
He was thrown out instead.
(Alex) Let it go, man.
Didn't I tell you before?
He's a proper pain.
He even pushes away the rep's chairs.
He's such a monster.
In fact, what you said about
his prescriptions is correct.
But we need to make him do it
our way, without him realising.
It's okay, sir.
I thought I might need it,
so I took an extra copy
from the training team.
Huh? What?
The Journal of Internal Medicine.
Wow!
Isn't that our main item, sir?
Yeah, of course!
Where is it? Let me see!
Here's it, sir.
Good you took an extra copy.
Give it to me.
How's my foresight, sir?
-(paper rips)
-Oh, no!
To hell with your journal!
This isn't the main item!
At the end of the month, you'll get
the sales report from the stockist.
That's the main item.
That's the only main item.
Got it, you idiot?
Trying to impress people.
If the sales go up,
you're the king.
Otherwise, you're a loser.
Your job is that simple.
And there he's complicating it!
(playful music)
Forget whatever those idiots
taught you during the training
and get into the market.
Got it?
When you come
for the next sales meeting,
you must arrive as a king.
Okay?
You know where the lodge is, right?
Carry on, then.
Bye.
(man) Buddy,
I had an awesome first day!
Got two prescriptions as well.
And such pretty nurses!
How was it for you?
I'll call you later.
Yeah, call me when you're free.
-Hello?
-(woman) Hey, K.P.
Why didn't you answer my call?
I was at my welcome party.
You know, my first day was awesome.
Got a few business deals, too.
-How was it for you?
-(indistinct chatter)
-K.P.?
-I'll call you later.
I'll call you back.
(fire crackles)
Doctor... chair for you.
(man 1) Did anyone
try putting it out?
(man 2) The doctor says
we can't go near the fire.
(man 1) Why not?
(man 2) He says poisonous gases
might come out of it.
-(man 1) Poisonous gases?
-(man 2) Those are drugs, right?
(man 2) So, he says
we can't go near it.
(man 1) Call the fire force then.
Let them come and put it out.
(fire crackling, whooshing)
(sombre music)
(fire crackling)
(siren blares)
(sombre music grows)
(closing theme music)